(綱手)いい天気だ。
しかし…
ったく 自来也のやつ➡
What a nice day…
But…
なんて後味の悪い話を
書きやがって。
Damn that Jiraiya!
Why'd he write a story with
such a bad ending?
続きが気になってしかたない。
I need to know how
the story continues…
(シズネ)あら
お茶をと思ったのですが➡
Oh…
I thought you might like
a little something for tea…
タイミングが悪かったでしょうか？
いや そんなことはない。
Perhaps this was a bad time?
No, not at all!
ちょうど小腹が
減っていたところだ。
I was feeling a little hungry…
(シズネ)よかった どうぞ
甘栗甘のよもぎ団子です。
Oh good. Please eat.
These are mugwort dumplings
from Amaguriama.
う～ん やはり
脳の疲れには甘いものだな。
There's nothing like something sweet
to wake up a tired mind!
どれ 続き続き。
Okay, continuing on.
PART TWO
(ミナト)キミたちのおかげで
任務は無事遂行された。
Thanks to your efforts,
the mission was successful.
ご苦労さま
と言いたいところだけど➡
Good job!
Is what I'd like to say…
But that's not quite
the case, is it?
そういうわけにもいかないよね。
I'm very sorry.
(ネジ)申し訳ありませんでした。
I'm the one
who disobeyed orders first.
最初に命令違反をしたのは俺です。
Please punish me
as you see fit.
どうか 俺を処分してください。
Neji, you aren't the only one at fault.
(リー)ネジ！
キミ一人のせいじゃありません。
He's right!
(ナルト)そうだってばよ。
んなこと言ったら 俺が最初に。
If you put it like that,
I was the first…
But…we had no choice at the time.
けど あの時は
それしかなかったんだ。
But breaking the rules
is breaking the rules.
(サスケ)だが 掟破りは掟破りだ。
But–!
Hey, this isn't the place to argue.
けどよ！
(カカシ)こら ここでもめない。
There's no doubt they may
have acted carelessly.
確かに 彼らの行動は
軽率だったかもしれません。
But their cleverness saved us.
That's a fact.
しかし 彼らの機転によって
我々が救われたのも事実。
Please go easy on them.
どうか 寛大な処置を
お願いします。
Well, since you put it like that…
キミたちに そう言われてはね。
Disobeying orders cannot
be overlooked.
確かに 命令違反は
許されるものじゃない。
But there are special circumstances
in all missions.
任務にはイレギュラーはつきもの。
Decisions must be made depending
on the situation at hand,
限られた状況のなかで判断し➡
and you must make
the best possible choice.
最良の選択を
していかなければならない。
In this case,
everyone joined together to
make the mission a success.
今回 キミたちは全員が団結して
事に当たり 任務を成功に導いた。
That has to be factored
into the evaluation.
その側面も評価しなければ
いけないよね。
Lord Fourth, does that mean…?
That no one is at fault…
I suppose.
(サクラ)四代目様 それって…。
(ヒルゼン)まっ お咎めなし
ということかのう。
Yes!
Way to go!
よっしゃ～！
やったってばよ。
(チョウジ)ひと安心したら
お腹減っちゃったよ。
(キバ)てっきり
大目玉食らうと思ったけどな。
Jiraiya Ninja Scrolls:
The Tale of Naruto the Hero-
Returning Home.
火影も しょせん
身内に甘いということか。
I thought he was gonna
give it to us!
お前 まだ言ってんのかよ。
俺は お前を認めない。
I guess Lord Hokage has
a soft spot for family members.
まあいいじゃねえか
せっかく丸く収まったんだしよ。
Are you still stuck on that?
それにしても ナルトの活躍ったら
すごかったよね。
I still don't acknowledge you.
Let it go already.
(いの)ほんと見直しちゃったわよ。
We got off easy and it's over.
Still, Naruto, you were amazing.
(ヒナタ)うん ナルト君
修業 頑張ってたもの。
Yeah, I see you in
a different light now.
アハハ！ それほどでもあるってばよ。
Yes, you really trained hard, Naruto.
よし 飯でも食いながら話そうぜ。
くだらん。
Well, yeah, I guess.
え～ サスケ君 帰っちゃうの？
Anyway, let's go get something
to eat and talk about it!
(チョウジ)まあいいじゃん いいじゃん
焼き肉だ！
So ridiculous.
Hey, are you leaving?
なんだよ あいつ。
Oh, just let him go.
It's barbecue time!
What is with that guy?
(綱手)面会謝絶だってのに
無理に押し入ってきやがって。
(自来也)お前は 大げさだのう。
LEAF HOSPITAL
I said no visitors!
And you push your way in.
ひどい状態は とっくに脱したわ。
You always overreact.
でも 心配なんだよ。
The situation is under control.
すみません うちの息子のせいで。
Still, I'm just worried.
なに かまうものか。
I'm sorry. My son is to blame.
この程度のケガ なんともないわい。
Don't worry about it.
An injury like this is nothing.
しかし ナルトのやつ➡
まだ つたないとはいえ
本当に九尾チャクラを操るとは。
Even though he's still a bit clumsy,
I can't believe how Naruto controlled
the Nine Tails' Chakra…
ひょっとしたら本当に➡
わしが捜し求めている
予言の子かもしれんのう。
Perhaps he really is
the "Child of Prophecy"
あれが
そんなたいそうなものかね…。
that I've been searching for.
ハハハハッ…。
You think he's that big of a deal?
しかし 安心してもおられん。
肝心の問題が残ったままだ。
But we can't rest easy.
There's still that one issue.
大蛇丸か。
わしが
あいつのアジトを見つけたとき…。
Orochimaru…
When I found his hideout…
((やっと見つけたぞ 大蛇丸。
I found you, Orochimaru.
(大蛇丸)フッ こんなところまで
訪ねてくるなんてね。
I can't believe you would actually
come all this way…
大蛇丸 その姿はいったい…。
Orochimaru, your appearance!
(大蛇丸)あぁ これ
新しい体を手に入れたのよ。
What in the…?
Oh this… I just obtained
a new body.
まさか 他人の体を
乗っ取ったというのか。
Don't tell me you hijacked
someone else's body?
不老長寿が 私の目標。
My goal is for perpetual youth
and longevity.
若く強く美しい体は
誰しもが憧れるもの。
To be young,
strong and beautiful.
It's what everyone yearns for.
ただ 今の この姿は仮の器。
But this is just a temporary vessel.
次に術が発動可能となる
３年後までには➡
In three years,
which is when I'll be able to
use this jutsu again,
もっと美しい体を見つけるつもり。
I'll find a body
that's even more beautiful.
そうはいかん。
お前の企みは ここまでよ！
Not likely.
Your scheme ends here!
土遁 黄泉沼！
Earth Style! The Dark Swamp!
残念 あなたの手の内は お見通し。
Too bad, I've already seen
through your tricks.
何だと!?
What?
He got away!
クッ 逃がしたか…。
だが わしは諦めん。
I'm not giving up.
If I look around, maybe I'll find
some clues to his next move…
探せば次の動きにつながる
痕跡くらいある。
This is–!
これは！
すぐに ミナトに知らせねば。
I have to let Minato
know right away.
Damn it!
(まずい… 口寄せの術！))
Summoning Jutsu!
From that scroll, there's no doubt
that Orochimaru was involved
あの巻物からするに
今回の事件に➡
in this recent incident…
大蛇丸が関わっていたことは
間違いないんだが…。
But we don't know what
to expect out of this.
思惑までは わからずじまいか…。
In any case,
we should be vigilant.
引き続き
警戒したほうがよさそうだのぉ。
Well then, I'd better do
what I can on my side.
なら 僕は僕で
できることは やっておかないと。
Excuse me.
失礼します。
Minato seems as busy as ever.
ミナトのやつ
相変わらず忙しそうだのぉ。
Well, we can't say the Hidden Leaf Village
is completely at peace.
そりゃあ 今の木ノ葉は➡
We were able to quell
a coup d'état by the Uchiha,
安定しているとは
言いがたいからな。
うちはのクーデターを
防ぐことはできたが➡
but we haven't gotten to
the root of the problem yet.
But Minato intends to use this
まだ根本は解決しておらん。
as an opportunity to
confront them directly.
しかし ミナトは これを機に連中と
向かい合ってみるつもりらしい。
Oh?
ほぉ。
(フガク)命令違反をしたあげく
余計なトラブルに巻き込まれるとはな。
うちは一族は ほぼ全員が
木ノ葉警務部隊に所属する名門。
So disobeying orders got you
involved in unnecessary trouble.
そんなざまでは示しがつかん。
Nearly everyone in
the Uchiha Clan is
a respected member of
the Leaf Police Force.
その…
勝手に飛び出した者がいて…。
止められなかったのなら
それは お前の力不足だろう。
This sets a bad example.
Well… There was someone
who acted recklessly!
はい。
Not being able to stop him
shows your inability.
(フガク)知ってのとおり 今は
うちは一族にとって大事な時期だ。
Yes.
お前の兄なら
もっとうまく立ち回ったろうに。
You must be aware that this is
a crucial time for the Uchiha.
Your older brother would
have done better.
(イタチ)失礼します。
(イタチ)
ただいま戻りました 父さん。
Excuse me.
おお 待っていたぞイタチ。
I'm back, Father.
まだ話し中かな？
(フガク)かまわん。
Oh, I've been waiting for you, Itachi.
それより
報告を聞かせてもらおうか。
Did I interrupt?
It's all right. Tell me what
you have to report.
俺は これで。
I'll excuse myself.
BARBE-Q
ん～ うまい！
任務のあとの焼き肉は 最高だね。
Delish!
ったく サスケのやつ
意地張りやがって。
There's nothing like barbecue
after a mission.
Damn Sasuke…
Acting stuck up…
(シカマル)
まあ あいつも忙しいんだろ。
くっそ～ ナルトばっかに
いいかっこされてたまるかよ。
Well, he could just be really busy…
Damn it, we can't let
Naruto show us up!
俺らも気合い入れて
修業しようぜ 赤丸！
Let's train hard from
now on too, Akamaru.
(赤丸)ワンワン！
それにしても
後味の悪い事件でしたね。
Still, this incident left
a bad aftertaste, didn't it?
うん。
最後にあんなことが
起こるなんて。
Who would have thought
it would end like that…
あいつら 意味わかんねえ。
I don't get them!
試験は終わったから 村人たちを
村に誘導するって言ってたのに。
Those guys said the stupid test
was over…
And that they needed to take
the villagers back to their homes.
まさか村ごと
吹っ飛ばしてしまうとはな。
I can't believe
they blew up the entire village.
僕たちが助けた
子供たちもいたのに。
The children we rescued
were there too.
おそらく
証拠隠滅のためでしょうが。
Perhaps they were erasing evidence?
(テンテン)だとしたら
とんでもない連中じゃない。
If that's the case,
they're horrible!
あんな連中に チーム・ジライヤを
名乗らせてたまるかよ！
They don't deserve to
call themselves Team Jiraiya…
今度 会ったらただじゃおかねえ！
If I see them again,
they're gonna pay!
そうよ！
絶対 捕まえてやるんだから！
That's right! We'll get them for sure!
ねえ シカマル。
Right, Shikamaru?
あ ああ… そうだな。
Y-Yeah…
父さんが言ったことは当然だ。
Father's right.
If Naruto hadn't acted on his own…
ナルトが勝手をしなければ。
(シロ)ワン ワン！
Shiro…
《シロ そういえばお前➡
Come to think of it…
あいつに助けられたんだったな》
He rescued you.
But it's different this time.
だが 今回は違う。
俺たちは任務のなかで動いていた。
We were in the middle of
a mission.
うまくいったのは
結果論にすぎない。
We were lucky it went well.
なのに みんなあいつに甘すぎる。
But even still,
everyone's too easy on the guy.
また父さんに何か言われたか？
Did Father lecture you again?
まあ いつもどおりかな。
そうか。
Well, it's nothing new.
だが 裏を返せば➡
I see.
But think of it this way… It's because
Father has high hopes for you.
それだけ
お前に期待してるってことだ。
それに 俺たちは今
微妙な立場にあるからな。
Also, our clan is in
a precarious position right now.
物騒なクーデターまで持ち出して…。
We attempted
a dangerous coup d'état…
強引に 火影に
こちらの条件をのませたばかりだ。
and forced the Hokage
to accept our conditions.
つけいられる隙を
作りたくないんだろう。
We can't afford to give him
any opportunity to reverse that.
祖先のマダラの反逆以降
その能力を恐れられ➡
Ever since the rebellion
by our ancestor Madara,
this ability of ours has been feared,
中央政治から遠ざけられてきた➡
and we were banished far
from the central government.
俺たちの状況を変えるために…。
In order to change our situation…
けど 約束は信じられるのか…。
But can we trust them to
keep their promise?
Don't worry.
心配ない。
That's why I've been assigned
to watch the Hokage.
それのために
俺が火影につけられている。
兄さん…。
Big Brother…
In time, you and I will be
the ones to support the Uchiha Clan.
いずれ 俺とお前が
うちは一族を支えることになる。
俺は 未来のために➡
In order to protect our future,
I intend to find out what
the Fourth is really thinking.
四代目の真意を
見極めるつもりだ。
So you have to hang in there too.
だから お前も頑張れ。
Big Brother is amazing!
《やはり 兄さんはすごい。
だが 俺だって…。
So I'm not about to let a guy
like that outdo me either!
あんなやつに
遅れを取ってる場合じゃない！》
俺に 新しい術を教えてくれ。
珍しいな。
ずいぶん やる気じゃないか。
Teach me a new jutsu.
俺には もっと力がいる。
What a surprise!
It's rare to see you so eager.
そのためには
決定力のある術が必要だ。
I need to get stronger.
フーン。
And I need to learn
a definitive jutsu for that.
それなら お誂え向きの術がある。
Well then, I have just
the perfect jutsu.
写輪眼の先読みと合わせて➡
初めて完成される
電光石火の貫通技…。
When combined with
the foresight of the Sharingan,
it culminates into a penetrating
technique of lightning speed.
つまり… 千鳥か。
In other words,
the Chidori, huh?
サスケのやつ
任務から帰ったばっかなのに➡
よく やるよね。
何言ってんの。
Even though we just got back
from a mission,
早速 新術の修業にかかるなんて
さすが サスケ君！
Sasuke's really working hard!
What are you saying?
Not missing a moment to
start training on a new jutsu
あんたたちも
少しは見習いなさいよ。
is just Sasuke for you.
めんどくせえなぁ。
You guys should be
more like him!
おい 今の話ほんとか？
What a drag.
サスケが
新しい術の修業をしてるって？
Hey, is that true?
Is Sasuke learning a new jutsu?
うん。 演習場でカカシ先生と。
Yeah.
マジか！
クッソ 出し抜かれたってばよ！
He's with Kakashi Sensei right now
at the training grounds.
Seriously?! Damn it!
おいおい 焦ることないだろ。
He's getting a leg-up on me!
つうかお前 すげえ術
会得したばっかじゃねえか…。
Hey, don't get all excited.
After all, you just mastered
an amazing jutsu yourself.
悪い また今度な！
Sorry, I'll see you guys later!
だから 面会謝絶だって
言ってるのに！
I told them, no visitors!
いいから どいてくれってばよ！
Come on…move over, will you?
なんだ 騒々しいのぉ…。
What's all the racket?
俺に修業をつけてくれってばよ！
エロ仙人！
I want you to train me, Pervy Sage!
ずいぶん性急な話だが…。
What brought this on
all of a sudden?
まあいい。 どうせ
しばらくは静養の身。
Whatever, okay.
I have to take it easy
for a while anyway.
ちょっくら見てやろうのぉ。
I'll watch over your training a little.
よっしゃ！
自来也…。
– All right!
– Jiraiya!
お～い！ サスケ！
Hey, Sasuke!
何の用だ。
俺も➡
What do you want?
I came to tell you that
I'm starting my training too!
修業 始めるって
言いにきたんだってばよ！
What?
何？
鈍いやつだな。
You're pretty dense, aren't you?
I'm saying that you'll have
to acknowledge me
お前より 先に新術を会得したら➡
when I master a new jutsu
before you do!
俺のこと 認めろって
言ってんだってばよ！
How stupid.
フン くだらん。
なんだと！
What did you say?!
I don't consider you competition.
お前など 相手にならない。
I have much higher goals.
俺の目標は
もっと先にあるからな。
I'll make you take back
those words!
その言葉 後悔すんなよ。
I swear it!
絶対 負かしてやっからな！
おい ナルト！
Hey, Naruto!
Sorry to interrupt!
フン！
邪魔したのぉ。
ハア… あいつ 何に勝つって？
What's he so worked up about?
I don't know.
Anyway, let's continue.
知らん。 それより 修業の続きだ。
らしくないのぉ
わざわざケンカを売りに行くとは。
It's unlike you to pick a fight.
いいんだ。 そのほうが
張り合いが出んだから。
Who cares?
This gets me more fired up!
あの小僧 お前の
負けたくない相手というわけか。
So he's the kid you don't
want to lose to?
しゃあっ！ 見てろよ サスケ！
Just watch me, Sasuke!
《俺は負けない。 そして➡
I won't lose.
一日も早く
父さんに認めてもらうんだ！》
And I'm going to get Father to
acknowledge me as soon as possible!
ハァーッ！
もっと集中しろのぉ。
Focus more!
確実に九尾のチャクラを引き出すんだ。
And pull out the Nine Tails
chakra with authority!
ハァーッ！
Did you hurt yourself?
ケガをしたか。
いや 問題ない。
No, it's nothing.
続けさせてくれ。
Let me continue.
ハァーッ！
(チョウジ)なんか サスケの修業ってさ
鬼気迫ってるよね。
Sasuke's training looks terrifying.
I'm kinda scared.
僕 ちょっと怖いんだけど。
Dummy! That's what makes it
so cool!
バカね あれがいいんじゃない。
あいつら いろいろ
めんどくせえからな。
Those guys are such a drag.
((ヒルゼン : うちはの件の報告書か。
ご意見番からの反対は
予想していましたが➡
Is this the report on
the Uchiha incident?
他の一族からの反発が
こうも強いとは。
I expected opposition
from the advisors,
皆怖いのだ。
裏切りの歴史があるうえ➡
but I didn't think there would be
such an uproar from the other clans.
基本的に他者と
交わろうとしないからな。
Everyone is afraid.
That clan has
a history of betrayal,
その高い能力と相まって
どうしても➡
and they tend to keep
to themselves.
得体の知れない連中と映る。
Coupled with their keen abilities,
they just appear more suspicious.
未然に終わったクーデターの件も
後を引いておるしな。
There are also
the lingering suspicions
しかし 約束を違えることは
できません。
surrounding the coup d'état
we just prevented.
わかっておるが これだけの
反対の声を無視しては➡
But we can't go back on our promise.
I know that.
それこそ 政に差し障る。
But the governing body can't ignore
説得を続けるしかないですね。
the voices of opposition
when it's this strong.
というわけだ
もう少し時間をくれないか？
We'll just have to keep trying
to persuade them.
Anyway, so that's the gist of it.
Can you give us
a little more time?
(イタチ)すみません
立ち聞きをしてしまいました。
力及ばず
申し訳ないと思ってる。
I beg your pardon…
I overheard you.
I'm sorry I wasn't able
to accomplish much.
(イタチ)いえ 少し驚きました。
No…
I'm actually a bit surprised.
しょせん
期限を切らない口約束➡
のらりくらりとかわされることも
考えていましたので。
I thought it was just
an empty promise
that you had no intention
of keeping.
それで欺かれるキミじゃないだろ。
You're not the type to be fooled
by something like that.
それに 力の及ぶ範囲の
災厄くらい➡
Besides, I want to prevent
any calamity
祓っていきたいからね。
that falls within my range of power.
自来也様が 妙木山で授かった
予言だよ。
When Master Jiraiya was
on Mount Myoboku,
忍世界には さまざまな災厄が
立ちはだかっている。
he was given a prophecy.
That the Shinobi World will
be wrought with many calamities…
で 自来也様の弟子の中から
現れる予言の子は➡
And among Master Jiraiya's pupils
is a "Child of Prophecy"
それらと戦う運命にあるらしい。
who is destined
to cast them away…
世界をよい方向に導くためにね。
in order to lead the world
in a better direction.
(イタチ)それは ナルト君のことですか？
Does that refer to Naruto?
さあね。 先生は多くの弟子を
持っているからね。
I don't know.
Sensei has many pupils.
俺も そのうちの一人だし。
I'm also one of them.
まっ それはともかくとして➡
In any case, villages plagued
with problems will be vulnerable.
問題を抱えた里はもろくなる。
俺の子や キミの弟…
次の世代のためにも➡
For my son and your younger brother…
For the next generation…
(なるべく平和な里を
残したいよね))
I want to leave them
a peaceful village.
ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
だいぶ形になってきたな。
It's taking shape considerably.
当然だ 立ち止まるわけには
いかない。
It better be.
I can't stop now.
With the state you're in,
we should call it a day.
その様子じゃ
今日はここまでだな。
We can resume tomorrow.
続きは 日を改めよう。
They're so carefree.
のんきなやつらだ。
Listen, Naruto.
(ミナト)いいかい？ ナルト。
This Rasengan is merely
the foundation.
この螺旋丸は
ただの基礎にすぎない。
おぉ～！
With further practice,
it can evolve into new jutsu.
この先の修業次第で➡
新しい術にも 進化させられる。
Father…
Oh, it was just you.
父さん。
お前だったか。
I've been practicing a new jutsu.
新術の修業をしていたんだ。
Is that so? Good for you.
そうか それはご苦労。
興味はないって感じか。
I guess he's not interested.
《いや 違う。
この程度では まだまだ➡
That's not it.
At this level, my jutsu isn't
worth the time for Father,
うちは一族を背負う
父さんの評価には➡
値しないってことだ…》
who's responsible for
the entire Uchiha Clan…
うぉ～っ！
さすがだな。
As expected…
まさか これほどのスピードで
習得するとは。
I'm amazed at how
you picked it up so quickly.
俺は うちはだからな。
That's because I'm an Uchiha.
This
《確かに この術なら➡
あれに 匹敵するかもしれない。
だが…》
《俺は あいつを凌駕する》
カカシ この千鳥➡
どこまで
進化させることができる？
ハァ 普通 少しは喜ぶもんだけどね。
まっ そういうところも
お前らしいか。
で どうなんだ？
正直 雷遁は
莫大なチャクラを使うからね。
チャクラ量の少ない俺には➡
これが 精いっぱいなんだよ。
不可能ってことか。
(カカシ)そうじゃない。
ただ この先は
相当な困難を極めるだろう。
クッ…。
(上條)ミツバチがいる場所には→
豊かな自然と
変わらぬ暮らしがあります。
残していきたい その風景。
美しき地球。